Let's talk the night away, young master.
我們聊個通宵吧,少主
Tell us about your worries as a youth.
跟我們說說年輕人的煩惱吧
You just want to be entertained by my stories!
你們只是想拿我的故事尋開心而已
Don't be ridiculous! I'm leaving! Let go!
別開玩笑了,我要走了,放手
Now, now... Feel free to tell us anything.
好了啦...想說什麼就說什麼吧
We're friends, aren't we?
我們是朋友,對吧?
Are we? Anyway, let go!
是嗎?給我放手啦
What's wrong? Get back at him!
怎麼搞的?打回去呀
Yeah! Right there!
好耶,就是那裡
Come on... Again?
不是吧...又來了?
- They're so stupid! - They fell!
-他們有夠笨的 -竟然跌到了
Is this a draw?
這樣算平手嗎?
None of you know anything.
你們什麼都不懂
You don't know anything.
你們什麼都不知道
You don't even know that you don't know.
你們甚至不知道自己很無知
If you don't even know that you don't know,
如果你們連自己很無知都不知道
there's no way you know anything about me.
你們絕對不可能了解我的處境
Well, I understand you, young master.
別這樣啦,少主,我很了解的
Seventeen is a very odd age.
17歲是一個尷尬的年紀
You're neither an adult nor a kid.
既不是成人也不是小孩
- Pour. - Yes.
-倒酒 -遵命
Here... There you go.
來囉,酒來囉
Look at you go!
真能喝啊
Fox, Badger...
狐、獾
I bet deep down, you two are laughing at me too.
我敢打包票 你們兩個骨子裡一定也在嘲笑我
This is going to be depressing.
這也太掃興了吧
That sobered me up. This was a bad idea.
我突然清醒了,這真是個壞主意
I can hear you!
我聽得見
You're nothing but bodyguards
你們只不過是保鏢而已
and you think you can look down on me?
竟然敢瞧不起我?
You just work for my dad for some meager wage.
你們只是為了那一丁點錢替我爸工作
Don't you have any pride as a warrior?
身為戰士,你們一點尊嚴都沒有嗎?
Please call us "guests."
請叫我們”客人”
Even people like us are rather useful during fights.
就連我們這種人 在打架的時候也很有用處喔
Oh yeah?
是嗎?
You guys actually work? I've never seen you do anything, Fox.
你們真的是來工作的嗎? 我從沒見過你們做過正事,狐
I know, right?
可不是嘛?
This village is so peaceful, it's so boring.
這個村落太祥和了,好無聊喔
Unsheathe it.
把劍亮出來
I'll check if you've become rusty or not.
我要看看生繡了沒
See?
看到了吧?
As guests, this is what the master pays us to do, after all.
身為客人,畢竟主人付錢給我們 就是為了做這種事
Damn it! Just kill me already!
可惡,乾脆殺了我吧
What should we do, Fox?
我們該怎麼辦,狐?
What went wrong?
怎麼會這樣?
We were supposed to drink and have fun and get on the Ketil family's good side.
我們不是只需要飲酒作樂 取悅凱特爾家的人就好了嗎?
I know, I'm pathetic!
我知道,我很可悲
So basically, what you don't like
所以,基本上,你不開心的原因
is the fact that the common people don't treat you
是因為一般人沒把你
like a grown man, right?
當成大人,是嗎?
You guys too!
你們也半斤八兩
Well, that can't be helped.
這顯然沒什麼幫助
You aren't a grown man after all.
畢竟你的確不是個大人
But to become a grown man--
但你若想當個大人...
Hey, try to comfort him.
喂,安慰安慰他吧
Shut up. I'm building up to that.
閉嘴啦,我正在往那個方向走
Just be quiet and listen.
安靜聽就對了啦
Hey, young master.
嘿,少主
- Damn it... - Becoming a grown man
-可惡 -要成為一個大人
is not that hard, you see.
其實並不困難
There's something like a rite of passage.
有一種類似成年儀式的東西
That's all you need to do.
你需要做的就只有這件事
It's the act of killing.
只需要殺人
Killing someone
奪取別人的性命
really boosts your confidence.
真的能夠提升你的自信心
You should experience it.
你該試試看
Once you learn how fragile the human body is,
一旦你知道了人的身體有多脆弱
you will stop fearing them.
你就不會再害怕他們了
It'll help you mature.
我會協助你成為成熟的大人
That is how all men grow up.
這就是男孩變成男人的方式
But... who?
但是...要殺誰?
That's obvious!
那很明顯吧
For beginners, there is beginner-level prey.
對於初學者而言 有屬於初學者的獵物
Don't worry.
別擔心
You can find them
你能夠在這座農場裡
on this very farm.
找到他們的
They are people you are allowed to kill.
他們是你可以殺的人
That was a good night's sleep.
昨晚睡得真好
I'm hungry.
我餓了
One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四
I guess today will be spent harvesting wheat again.
我想今天一整天又得收割小麥了
This farm is way too big.
這座農場實在太大了
At this rate,
按照這種速度
we won't be able to clear the land during springtime.
我們會來不及在春天結束前整地完成
Ideally, I want it to be ready for sowing in the fall.
理想狀況下,我希望這片土地 能夠整理就緒,讓我在秋天播種
First we have to dig out the roots and rocks,
我們首先要把樹根和石頭挖出來
then turn over the soil, then let the soil rest...
然後再鬆土,讓土壤休息
Would they let us borrow a heavy plow?
他們會願意把重型耕犁借給我們嗎?
Thorfinn! What's wrong?
托爾芬,你怎麼了?
Are you dreaming? Thorfinn!
你做惡夢了嗎,托爾芬?
Are you okay?
你沒事吧?
You seemed really distressed.
你看起來真的很痛苦
How bad was the dream that it would make you like that?
是什麼樣的惡夢能讓你變成這樣?
Dream?
是個夢?
What was it?
我夢到了什麼?
I can't remember.
我不記得了
Well, go wash your face. Then we can start our morning chores.
先去洗把臉 然後就開始進行晨間雜務吧
Dreams you can't remember are better off forgotten...
不記得的夢境,忘了也好
Good morning.
早安
It's a beautiful day, isn't it?
今天天氣真好,對吧?
Yes! Good morning!
對呀,早安
Do you want to wash your face? Go ahead.
你們要洗臉嗎?來吧
I've used it already.
我已經洗好了
Oh, no! Okay! Sorry! Take your time!
不用啦,沒關係 不好意思,妳慢慢來
I mean,
我是說...
there's no point in washing a face like mine anyway!
我這張臉也沒什麼好洗的
Oh, don't say that...
千萬別這麼說
I think you have a lovely face.
我覺得你的臉很可愛
Are you okay?
你沒事吧?
- Are you hurt somewhere? - No, it's my heart...
-你哪裡受傷了嗎? -不是,是我的心...
Oh no! Does it hurt?
不是吧,很痛嗎?
No, I'm fine! It's not an illness or anything.
沒有啦,我沒事,我不是生病啦
- Is it a wound? - Um, no...
-是傷口嗎? -呃,不是啦
What is this?
怎麼搞的?
I feel uneasy.
我覺得很不安
I have a feeling that dream was something
我有種感覺,我似乎不該忘記
I shouldn't forget.
夢境的內容
My name is Arnheid.
我叫阿奴納
You arrived here recently, right?
你才剛來這裡沒多久,對吧?
Yes! I am Einar. I came from England.
對,我叫埃納爾,來自英格蘭
Oh, England?
英格蘭喔?
You're so fluent,
你說得好流利
I assumed you were Nordic.
我還以為你是北方人
Yes, everyone in my hometown,
沒錯,我家鄉的人,包括我
including me, was of Nordic descent.
我們的祖先全都是北方人
Everyone in the village spoke English and Norse.
村裡的人都會說英語和諾斯語
I have a thick accent,
我的口音很重
so it may be hard to understand, ma'am.
可能不容易理解,女士
Oh, that's right. I'm sorry...
喔,對了,很抱歉
I haven't told you about myself, have I?
我還沒自我介紹,對吧?
You're not the master's daughter?
妳不是主人的女兒嗎?
No, I'm not.
不,我不是啦
I'm a slave, just like you.
我跟你一樣是奴隸
I am the master's personal maid.
我是主人的貼身女僕
Good morning, all of you.
大家早安
What is this? Are the slaves planning an escape this morning?
怎麼回事?奴隸們 今天早上在商量如何逃跑嗎?
Good morning.
早安
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字?
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
Are you a slave too?
你也是奴隸嗎?
You don't look familiar.
好像沒見過你
I'm Einar. I've been here since the summer.
我叫埃納爾 我從夏天開始就待在這裡了
Thorfinn and Einar.
托爾芬和埃納爾
Come with us for a second.
跟我們來一下
This has become one busy morning.
今早還真忙碌啊
Who are they?
他們是什麼人?
They're carrying swords.
身上戴著劍
They're not regular people, right?
他們不是普通人,對吧?
They're guests...
他們是客人
A defense force that resides on this farm.
是駐紮在這座農場的防衛兵力
They're bodyguards.
他們是保鏢
And they have business with us?
他們跟我們有什麼瓜葛嗎?
I doubt it's going to be anything good.
我想準沒什麼好事
I think you have a lovely face.
我覺得你的臉很可愛
You seem to be in a good mood, Einar.
埃納爾,你的心情似乎很不錯
Oh, sorry.
呃,抱歉
No worries!
沒關係啦
You look like the lively type.
你看起來就是個很有活力的人
All right, young master.
好的,少主
Go ahead and slash them! Slash!
去吧,像這樣砍下去,砍吧
Slash? Don't tell me...
像這樣砍下去?不是吧?
Yes, big one. That's right.
是的,大塊頭,沒錯
What?
什麼?
It's a ceremony for the young master to become an adult.
這是少主的成年儀式
Die for us, will you?
你們就乖乖送死吧
Don't be ridiculous!
別開玩笑了
What wrong did we do to deserve such treatment?!
我們犯了什麼錯? 為什麼要受到這種待遇?
You didn't do anything wrong.
你們沒做錯任何事
It's just that your life doesn't belong to you.
只是你們的性命不屬於你們
That's all.
這樣罷了
The rightful owner is free to do whatever he pleases with his possessions.
合法的主人可以隨心所欲地 處置他們的財產
You guys are slaves belonging to Master Olmar's family.
你們是歐瑪家族的奴隸
He is going to kill you himself. You should be honored.
他會親手殺了你,你該感到很榮幸
Good for you!
說得好
Just give up.
你們就認命吧
These guys
這些人
belong to my dad.
是屬於我爸爸的
They're not mine.
不是我的
If I kill them, I have to pay compensation.
如果我殺了他們,我就得付賠償金
How pitiful, young master!
太可悲了吧,少主
You're saying that this late in the game?
事情都走到這一步了 你說的那是什麼話?
Are you scared of your father?
你害怕你父親嗎?
Are you scared of killing?
你不敢殺人嗎?
Or maybe both?
還是兩者都對?
Shut up! I'm not scared of anything!
閉嘴,我什麼都不怕
Then let's get to it! Just slash them!
那就動手吧,砍下去就對了
Thorfinn, run away.
托爾芬,快跑
It's fine!
沒關係啦
Damn it!
可惡
What are you doing? Go and tell the master, Thorfinn!
你在做什麼,托爾芬? 快跑去告訴主人
Come on! You can do it, young master! Your opponent is ready to fight!
加油,你可以的,少主 你的對手準備要跟你打了
Don't move, kid.
別動,孩子
Just watch quietly.
安靜地看就好
What a drag...
真麻煩
You can cut me.
你來砍我吧
Go, young master!
加油,少主
One person is enough, right?
一個人就夠了,對吧?
Please let him go back to work.
請讓他回去工作吧
You can cut me.
你可以砍我
Ouch...
好痛
It's morning?
早上了嗎?
Hey, Gramps!
喂,老頭子
Gramps! Are you not here?
老頭子,你不在嗎?
Gramps!
老頭子
Where's my breakfast?
我的早餐呢?
What are you talking about, waking up so late?!
這麼晚才起床,還在那邊大呼小叫?
If you want to eat,
如果想吃東西
why don't you help out with the harvest once in a while!
那就偶爾來幫忙收割吧
No way!
才不要
Then I won't feed you!
那我不會給你飯吃
Fend for yourself.
你自己想辦法吧
Damn you, Gramps.
可惡,老頭子
I'm not going through the trouble of cooking.
我才懶得煮飯
Oh well, I guess I'll head back.
好吧,那我就回去吧
Master Olmar can cut me.
歐瑪主人可以砍我
Please let Einar go back to work.
請讓埃納爾回去工作
Today's a busy day.
今天很忙
What did you say?
你說什麼?
Sorry, what was your name again?
不好意思,你說你叫什麼名字?
I'm Thorfinn.
托爾芬
do you understand what you just said?
你知道你說了什麼嗎?
If you let him cut you, you're going to die.
如果你讓他砍你,你會死掉的
Right...
沒錯
You idiot!
你這個笨蛋
What are you saying--
你在說什麼...
You stay quiet. It's not your place to butt in.
你給我安靜,沒有你說話的餘地
Did you all hear him?
你們全都聽到他說的了?
Once in a while, you meet people like him.
偶爾也是會遇見一個像他這樣的人啦
You know,
你知道
I just can't ignore those kinds of statements.
那種話我無法裝作沒聽到
If I let them slide,
如果我就這樣算了
they will bring down the value of our commodity.
那會拉低我們的商品價值
Say, Thorfinn,
那麼,托爾芬
what kind of commodity do you think
你認為我們這種戰士
warriors like us handle?
能夠處理什麼樣的商品呢?
Who knows...
誰知道?
It's death.
死亡
No matter who it is, everyone is afraid to die.
不管是誰,每個人都怕死
No matter who it is. I can say for certain.
無論誰都一樣,這點我很有把握
Take a look at the young master.
看看少主吧
He's even afraid of someone else's death.
他甚至害怕別人死亡
Shut up! I'm not afraid.
閉嘴,我才不怕
That's fine, though.
這樣也沒關係
It has value because people are afraid of it.
生命有價值,是因為大家怕死
If not, we wouldn't be able to make a living with a sword.
如果不是這樣的話 我們就不能靠劍謀生了
I'm sure you're afraid too.
我肯定你也怕死
Be afraid.
怕了吧?
I'm so hungry.
我好餓喔
Hey, you hoodlums!
喂,你這個流氓
Stop it, you guys!
你們住手
Jeez, those idiots.
去你的,那些笨蛋
They're causing trouble again.
又在惹麻煩
Stop it!
住手
Damn it! You bastards!
該死,你們這些渾球
Come on.
來吧
Beg for your life.
求饒吧
Don't be stubborn,
別固執了
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
Ouch...
好痛
You'd better hurry, or else your tiny body
你最好動作快,不然你瘦小的身體
will become even smaller!
會變得更瘦小
He didn't even bat an eye.
他的眼睛連眨都沒眨一下
That's impressive.
厲害
If I remember correctly, he's the master's slave...
如果我記得沒錯的話 他是主人的奴隸
- Just kill him! - Do it!
-殺了他吧 -動手
Why...
為什麼...
do I have to be afraid to die?
我得怕死?
Are you living because you don't want to die?
你們活著的原因是因為怕死嗎?
Is there anything...
活著...
good that comes from being alive?
有任何好處嗎?
I can't think of anything.
我想不出任何好處
Of all the years I have lived, I have never once
在我活著的這些年當中,我從來沒有
been glad that I was alive.
因為活著感到開心過
Next, it'll be your eye.
接下來是你的眼睛
Be afraid.
怕了吧?
Stop, Fox!
狐,住手
Huh? Snake?
咦?蛇?
How terrible.
太慘了吧
Boss... welcome back. When did you...?
老大...歡迎回來,你什麼時候...
- Fox. - Yes, sir!
-狐 -是,老大
- Come here.
-過來 -遵命
- Badger. - Yes, sir!
-獾 -我在,老大
Explain.
給我解釋清楚
Awakening.
甦醒
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯:歐德慧